Airborne to be wild.
Zambezia is a comedy, animation, adventure film directed by Wayne Thornley.
Set in a bustling bird city on the edge of the majestic Victoria Falls, "Zambezia" is the story of Kai - a naïve, but high-spirited young falcon who travels to
the bird city of "Zambezia" where he discovers the truth about his origins and, in defending the city, learns how to be part of a community.
Tendai (voice), played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Zoe (voice), played by Abigail Breslin.
Sekhuru (voice), played by Leonard Nimoy.
Kai (voice), played by Jeremy Suarez.
Ajax (voice), played by Jeff Goldblum.
Gogo (voice), played by Jenifer Lewis.
Adventures in Zambezia, or simply Zambezia, is a 2012 South African animated adventure comedy film directed by Wayne Thornley, written by Andrew Cook,
Raffaella Delle Donne, and Anthony Silverston, and stars the voices of Jeremy Suarez, Abigail Breslin, Jeff Goldblum, Leonard Nimoy, and Samuel L.
Jackson, with Jim Cummings, Richard E.
Grant, Jenifer Lewis, Jamal Mixon, and David Shaughnessy in supporting roles.
In the film, Kai, a peregrine falcon journeys to the titular city which is
in a colossal Baobab tree on the edge of Victoria Falls.
Adventures in Zambezia is the first film produced by Triggerfish Animation Studios and
distributed by Cinema Management Group and Sony Pictures in English territories.
Adventures in Zambezia was theatrically released on 3 July 2012
and earned $34.4 million on a R173 million budget.
It received Annie Award nominations for Music in an Animated Feature
Production and for Voice Acting in an Animated Feature Production.
The film won the Best South African Feature Film at the
Durban International Film Festival in 2012.
It also won Best Animation at the South African Film and Television Awards
and Best Animation at the 9th Africa Movie Academy Awards.
The tone is lighthearted.